Ankit Kelkar

Charlotte, NC (Open to relocate) | Email: ankit.kelkar@gmail.com | Phone:+1980-430-9833

Website: https://akelkar3.github.io/portfolio | LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/AnkitKelkar | Github: akelkar3

Highlights

7+ years of experience in software development with Agile and continuous integration/ continuous delivery practices. A go to person in team to implement new and cutting-edge technologies for Proof of Concepts and front-end work

Graduation: Dec 2018

Education

Master of Science in Computer Science

University of North Carolina at Charlotte, NC, USA

Specialization in Visualization with GPA 3.9

Skills

Languages: C#, C++, Java, Python, JavaScript, Swift 4.0

Tools: Unity 3D, Blender, AutoCAD, OpenGL, OpenCV, Android Studio, Eclipse, Xamarin, MATLAB 7.7, XCode, Vuforia, AR Core, AR Kit Web Technologies: .NET MVC, SQL Server 2012 MVVM, Bootstrap, CSS, NodeJS, MongoDB, ExpressJS, AngularJS, HTML5, JQuery, AWS, WCF, Entity framework

Experience

Developer Jan 2019 – Present

MIAC Analytics

Web Application Development

- Developing a financial trading application using .Net Core web api, Angular JS, Angular
- Implemented integration with SSRS reporting which saved more than 70% time for reporting than previous method
- Lead the implementation of hybrid angular application for large application and migration to Angular 11 application.
- Developed an interactive visualization tool for comparing best-ex providing a better user experience.
- Implemented continuous integration continuous delivery through Bamboo to ensure quality deployment.

Intern May 2018 – Dec 2018

MicroD Inc

Augmented Reality Development in 3D team

- Developing an Augmented Reality application for iOS/ Android/ HoloLens
- Rendering 3D objects through C# and web service integration
- Compared different AR Apis available for augmented reality like Vuforia, ARCore, ARKit
- Implemented MVC framework for Unity3D
- Implemented continuous integration continuous delivery through Jenkins saving deployment time

Graduate Assistant Feb 2018- Aug 2018

University of North Carolina at Charlotte

Augmented Reality Development

- Displaying demographic Data using mobile and HoloLens
- Developing a mobile application for Augmented Reality using Vuforia
- Developed 3D assets using Blender
- Exhibited the project in Urban Planning Symposium and OpenStreets704 events

Graduate Assistant Feb 2018- March 2018

University of North Carolina at Charlotte

Full Stack Web application development

• Deploying a NodeJS server on a Linux system for Authentication page

• Developing an WSO2 Authentication for role-based authentication

Senior System Engineer Aug 2013 – June 2017

Infosys Limited, Pune, India

Business/Supplier Portal: Web application for Sales Team

- Maintained and upgraded web application using .NET MVC4, jQuery, WCF, Entity framework and SQL Server.
- Designed UI for the application using Knockout JS and Bootstrap library.
- Developed reporting for the web application for the users.
- Performed various code optimization tasks and load testing.
- Drafted proof of concepts for various suggestion for website development to client which were highly appreciated.
- Generated Monthly and Weekly status report for team in the Agile development model.
- Trained in Responsive mobile app development using Angular Js and PhoneGap

Technical Projects

Mobile Application Development

Aug 2017 - Dec 2018

University of North Carolina at Charlotte, NC

- Developed full stack application using NodeJs, ExpressJS, MongoDB and MySQL with mobile app as front-end
- UI and Web application development for various apps.
- Integration of Google Maps/ Firebase Realtime Database/ Firebase Authentications APIs

Visualization of Layout of a floor for Emergency Rescue Purposes

Aug 2017 - Dec 2018

University of North Carolina at Charlotte, NC

- Visualized a floor layout using Holo-lens
- Implemented Unity Networking for connecting two holo-lenses with server
- Visualized shortest available path to the rescue personnel through graphics aid.
- Developed Augmented Reality environment using Vuforia.

An automation system to sort threaded and unthreaded nuts using Image Processing

July 2012 - June 2013

Abhijay Group of industries

- Installed a machine vision system at the end of manufacturing line .
- Sorted the correct and incorrect parts using image processing algorithm
- Reduced human introduced counting errors and increased efficiency by 300%.
- Developed the system using Beagle-Bone hardware and OpenCV for image processing.
- Designed system's body and holder on manufacturing line using CATIA.

Simulation of Dynamic Channel Allocation (DCA) using interference aware algorithm Bharti Airtel pvt. Ltd.

March 2011 - May 2012

- Performed thorough survey of existing methods of communication channel allocation in telecommunication industry.
- Researched for one of the better approaches available.
- Simulated a scenario for getting statistical outputs of implementation of the Dynamic Channel Allocation.
- Brief introduction about GSM architecture Experience in MATLAB programming and simulation of a communication scenario.

Achievements

| • | Wolffall Award in Hackathon at Duke Oniversity | 2010 |
|---|---|------|
| • | Project got Exhibited at Urban Planning Symposium and OpenStreets704 events | 2018 |
| • | Awarded Star performer in year for project work | 2013 |